在高中或工程数学中，您可能会遇到复杂数字的概念。
In high school or Engineering Maths, you’ve probably come across the concept of a complex number.
一个数字有两个组成部分，一个是真实的组件和一个虚构的组件。
A number has got two components, a real component and an imaginary component.
虚部是真实的标量B乘以虚数i，i是
The imaginary component is a real scalar B multiplied by the imaginary number i, i being
-1的平方根。
the square root of -1.
我们可以将这个概念扩展到所谓的超复数。
We can extend this concept to what’s called a hypercomplex number.
现在，我们不是只有一个虚数i，而是有虚数i，j，
Now, instead of having just one imaginary number i, we have imaginary numbers i, j,
和k。
and k.
它们各自是-1的平方根，它们的乘积等于-1。
They are each the square root of -1 and their product is equal to -1.
因此，超复数的数字有一个实部和三个虚部。
So, the hypercomplex number has got one real part and three imaginary parts.
超复数数字通常写为标量加上向量，s加v。
Hypercomplex numbers are typically written as a scalar plus a vector, s plus v.
超复数的概念可以追溯到爱尔兰数学家威廉
The concept of hypercomplex numbers can be traced back to the Irish mathematician, William
汉密尔顿。
Hamilton.
故事说有一天，他正沿着都柏林的运河走，关键等式，
The story goes that one day, he was walking along the Canal in Dublin and the key equation,
i2=j2=k2=ijk=-1进入了他的大脑。
i2 = j2 = k2 = ijk = -1 came in to his brain.
而且，他将方程式雕刻在桥梁的一块石头上。
And, he carved the equation in to a stone on the wall of the bridge.
而且，今天在这座特殊的桥上有一块铭牌，以纪念这一天才的闪光
And, there is today a plaque on this particular bridge which commemorates this flash of genius
和灵感。
and inspiration.
超复数是我们称之为四元数的数学对象的基础。
The hypercomplex number is the basis of a mathematical object that we call a quaternion.
我将四元数表示为Q，上面有一个小圆圈。
I denote a quaternion as a Q with a little circle above it.
所以，我们在s+v处写它.S是一个真正的标量，v是表示复数的向量
So, we write it at s + v. S is a real scalar and v is a vector representing the complex
这个数字的一​​部分。
part of this number.
四元数通常以这种形式写成，我们有s然后是内角
Quaternions are often written in this form as well where we have s and then inside angle
括号中，我们有三个元素的向量部分，三个虚部
brackets, we have the three elements of the vector part, the three imaginary parts of
四元数。
the quaternion.
编写四元数有很多种不同的方法。
There are quite a few different ways of writing quaternions.
这是我将在本讲座中使用的方式以及机器人工具箱的方式
This is the way that I will use in this lecture and also the way that the robotics Toolbox
表示MATLAB中的四元数。
represents a quaternion in MATLAB.
正如我们可以确定矢量的大小或长度一样，我们可以确定幅度
Just as we can determine the magnitude or length of a vector, we can determine the magnitude
或四元数的长度，它是四个数字元素之和的平方根
or length of a quaternion and it’s the square root of the sum of the four numeric elements
四元数，它是真实的部分和三个虚部。
of the quaternion, it’s real part and the three imaginary parts.
现在，我们得到所谓的单位四元数，这是一个四元数，其大小是
Now, we get to what’s called a unit quaternion and this is a quaternion whose magnitude is
等于1。
equal to 1.
单位四元数特别有用，因为我们可以使用它们来编码三个旋转
Unit quaternions are particularly useful because we can use them to encode rotation in three
维度空间。
dimensional space.
单位四元数与角度和轴表示有很多相似之处
A unit quaternion has a lot of similarities to the angle and axis representation that
我们在上一节讨论过。
we discussed in the last section.
单位四元数的实部等于旋转角的一半的余弦
The real part of the unit quaternion is equal to the cosine of half the rotation angle and
我在这里用n-hat表示的旋转轴与矢量部分有关
the rotation axis which I have denoted here by n-hat is related to the vector part of
这种关系的四元数涉及旋转角度的一半的正弦。
the quaternion by this relationship which involve sine of half the rotation angle.
我可以复合两个单位四元数。
I can compound two unit quaternions.
就像我们可以复合两个旋转矩阵一样，我可以复合两个四元数而且它是
Just as we can compound two rotation matrices, I can compound two quaternions and it’s
通过使用这个，所谓的汉密尔顿主义产品规则。
done by using this, what’s called the Hamiltonian product rule.
因此，四元数1将我从A帧旋转到B帧。四元数2使我从帧旋转
So, quaternion 1 rotates me from frame A to frame B. Quaternion 2 rotates me from frame
B到框架C，然后，产品是从框架A到框架C的旋转。并且，我可以计算
B to frame C, then, the product is the rotation from frame A to frame C. And, I can compute
四元数的倒数。
the inverse of a quaternion.
因此，如果我使用四元数将我从第A帧旋转到第B帧，则反转非常简单。
So if I use a quaternion to rotate me from frame A to frame B, the inverse is quite simple.
这只是四元数的向量部分的否定。
It’s just the negation of the vector part of the quaternion.
再一次，我将创建一个相当随意的旋转矩阵。
Once again, I’m going to create a fairly arbitrary rotation matrix.
从一些欧拉角开始，将它们转换为旋转矩阵0.1,0.2,0.3，只是
Going to start with some Euler angles, convert them to rotation matrix 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, just
为了说明的目的。
for the purpose of illustration.
这里我们有一个旋转矩阵。
Here we have a rotation matrix.
现在，我将创建一个四元数，我使用四元数类，然后传入
Now, I’m going to create a quaternion and I use the quaternion class and I pass in as
一个参数一个旋转矩阵。
an argument a rotation matrix.
并且，结果是一个四元数对象，我们可以在工作区中看到它。
And, the result is a quaternion object which we can see in our workspace.
现在，四元数有一个真实的部分和一个虚部，在里面表示
Now, the quaternion has got a real part and an imaginary part, which is indicated inside
尖括号。
the angle brackets.
我要将四元数放入一个名为Q的永久变量中，让我们看看
I’m going to park the quaternion into a permanent variable called Q and let’s look
在MATLAB中我们可以用这个四元数对象做什么。
at what we can do with this quaternion object in MATLAB.
我可以做的一件事是我可以绘制这个四元数并查看方向
One of the things that I can do is I can plot this quaternion and look at the orientation
它的行为就像我们之前看到的trplot函数一样。
and it behaves just like the trplot function that we looked at earlier.
我可以计算四元数的倒数，这里它就在这里，我们可以看到
I can compute the inverse of the quaternion, and here it is here, and we can see that the
四元数的实部保持不变，但向量部分被否定。
real part of the quaternion remains unchanged, but the vector part is negated.
如果我将四元数乘以其反转，则结果为零四元数。
If I multiply the quaternion by its inverse, the result is the null quaternion.
这有一个矢量分量等于0。
This has got a vector component equal to 0.
所以这表示0转。
So this indicates a 0 rotation.
我也可以使用MATLAB中的除法运算符来计算它。
I can also compute that using the division operator in MATLAB.
所以，如果我采用四元数并有效地将其除以四元数，它就是一样的
So, if I take a quaternion and effectively divide it by the quaternion, it’s the same
乘以其倒数。
as multiplying by its inverse.
我再次获得零旋转。
I once again get the zero rotation.
如果我有一个四元数并且我将它乘以一个向量，那么假设一个向量是一个单位向量
If I have a quaternion and I multiply it by a vector, let’s say a vector is a unit vector
在x方向上，我通过转置它将其转换为列向量，然后是这个符号
in the x direction and I turn it to a column vector by transposing it, then what this notation
在MATLAB中，我们将矢量乘以四元数。
in MATLAB does is to multiply the vector by the quaternion.
实际上，它会旋转矢量。
Effectively, it rotates the vector.
最后，我可以举一个例子来说明插值。
Finally, I can do an example to illustrate interpolation.
如果我调用没有参数的四元数，它将返回一个对应于的四元数
If I call quaternion with no arguments, it returns a quaternion corresponding to the
空旋转。
null rotation.
所以，如果我使用这样的MATLAB语法，我会使用我的零四元数，用它插入它
So, if I use MATLAB syntax like this, I take my null quaternion, interpolate it with the
我有其他四元数，Q和我传入一个告诉我插值的参数
other quaternion I have, Q, and I pass in an argument which tells me the interpolation
分数。
fraction.
因此，这是在四元数Q0，零旋转和四元数之间进行插值
So, this is interpolating between the quaternion Q0, the null rotation, and the quaternion
问：最后一个参数是插值距离。
Q. The last argument is the interpolation distance.
0对应于初始四元数。
0 corresponds to the initial quaternion.
1对应于最终的四元数。
1 corresponds to the final quaternion.
如果我传入0，结果应该是我们的初始四元数。
If I pass in 0, the result should be our initial quaternion.
将其设为1，结果将是我们的最终四元数。
Make it 1, the result will be our final quaternion.
如果我输入类似0.5的东西，这是在初始值之间的插值
And if I put in something like 0.5, this is an interpolation halfway between the initial
四元数和最终四元数。
quaternion and the final quaternion.
因此，这是一种插值表示为四元数的旋转的方法。
So this is a way to interpolate rotations that are represented as quaternions.